JOSEPHFALVELLA@ALUM.MIT.EDU | LINKEDIN.COM/IN/FALVELLA

INTERNATIONAL PLAZA 10 ANSON ROAD, 37-10 SINGAPORE 079903

+65 8313 3266

November 20, 2016

To whom it may concern,

I write to you expressing interest in roles currently open at your firm, and my resume is attached for review.

Let me assure you that my background is unlike most of the candidates that you may have seen, giving me a unique perspective. My non-traditional career path consists of over 12 years of experience in business development, operations, and strategy. Following those career experiences, I put myself through college while operating my own business, and recently earned multiple degrees, including a master's degree from MIT (Massachusetts Institute of Technology).

After reviewing the roles and the required background in which your firm is looking for, I am confident that my abilities match the needs and the culture of your firm perfectly. For example, I possess:

- Experience in enterprise asset management, strategy consulting, financial analysis, and value realization across several industries, including FMCG, luxury goods, technology, automotive, and real estate
- Stellar leadership and project management skills; ability to engage and lead multi-cultural teams for timely delivery and execution. Exceptional interpersonal skills building relationship with internal/external clients
- Ability to operate strategically and tactically in intense environments with a high degree of organization while managing multiple and competing priorities. Career experience in Southeast Asia and USA
- Experience delivering professional services focused on complex business problems involving commercial and operational due diligence, post-merger integration and operational restructuring

I completed my post graduate rotation and consulting projects in Singapore and I am currently holding a private equity related role in a global firm that I took on while I was finishing my degree from MIT. I am now seeking something more challenging and rewarding in which to apply my talents. I look forward to the opportunity to convey my strengths in an in-person interview.

Regards,

Joseph Falvella

3 acept fahrella

JOSEPH FALVELLA

JOSEPHFALVELLA@ALUM.MIT.EDU | LINKEDIN.COM/IN/FALVELLA

INTERNATIONAL PLAZA 10 ANSON ROAD, SUITE 37-10 SINGAPORE 079903

+65 8313 3266

An experienced professional and recent graduate from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, with a background in management, business development, finance, client facing sales, operations, and strategy across industry sectors. Demonstrable history of creating true followership, working effectively with top management and CEOs, and helping clients realize their full economic potential. Seeking a mid to senior level role in consulting / sales / banking / business development - Singapore



EDUCATION

MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - CAMBRIDGE, MA

JUNE 2016

Master of Engineering (School of Engineering & Sloan School of Management) GPA 4.5 MIT - SUTD Scholar

- Professional master's degree covering management, finance, operations, and strategy
- Visiting scholar at the Singapore University of Technology and Design (SUTD) | Feb-Dec 2015

University of Virginia - Charlottesville, VA

AUGUST 2012

Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering (Design & Entrepreneurship) Major GPA 3.7 with Distinction Associate of Science (VCCS), Business Administration (Finance & Marketing) Major GPA 3.8 Magna Cum Laude

• Phi Theta Kappa International Honor Society, Pi Tau Sigma Engineering Honors, National Science Foundation Scholar

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PRIVATE EQUITY OFFICER - STATE STREET CORPORATION, ALTERNATIVE INVESTMENTS, SINGAPORE JANUARY 2016 - PRESENT

- Oversee 3000 funds in private equity, real estate, and infrastructure; clients in Korea, Japan, and Singapore
- Lead team of Associate I, II and Senior Associates in Singapore and China, supervising workflow and client deadlines
- Manage and grow relationships with clients, personnel, and fund investors. Assist in onboarding process of new clients
- Liaise between general partners, limited partners, and institutional managers for monthly and quarterly deliverables

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT & VISITING SCHOLAR – POST-GRADUATE ROLE AT SUTD, SINGAPORE

2014-2016

- Developed market entry strategies for start-up companies out of the MIT SUTD International Design Center
- Managed and built strategic partnerships and opportunities with Fortune 500 companies, identified client opportunities
- Performed qualitative and quantitative data analysis; assessed product and market trends, delivered go-to-market strategies
- Conducted due diligence, analyzed industry, extracted key findings, compiled reports and slide decks for end deliverables
- Provided mentorship/leadership to junior members, promoted strategic thinking and tailored approach to meet project needs

CONSULTANT | OPERATIONS & STRATEGY (POST-MERGER INTEGRATION) - MIT INTERNSHIP - LENZE AMERICA

2012 - 2013

- Liaised with top management from U.S and Germany for post-merger integration and enterprise asset/risk management
- Designed and implemented target operating model with Day 1/Day 100 planning, performed operational due diligence
- Capitalized on latent synergies, managed work streams, led 200 employee engagement for execution and implementation
- Delivered 6-month capacity building plan with financial analysis to the CEO, enabling merger of overseas division
- Reduced future CapEx by \$12M, improved ROA, raised revenue capability from \$45M to \$120M

STRATEGY CONSULTANT - TIME MAGAZINE BEST TECH INNOVATION 2012 | LIQUIGLIDE, CAMBRIDGE, MA

2012-2013

- Managed a team of 5 consultants tasked with market expansion for MIT spin-off company LiquiGlide
- Identified CPG market opportunities, conducted financial analysis of expansion options, wrote business plan
- Delivered market entry and risk mitigation strategy to the CEO; company now expanded to clients in 7 countries

- Investment in the acquisition, value improvement, and sale of distressed real estate & vintage automobiles
- Determined target investments, executed due diligence, valuations, managed capital, purchasing, and sales
- Project management and engineering; complete restoration of several historic properties and investment vehicles
- Diverse knowledge/experience in mechanical, electrical, and structural/architectural systems, interior/exterior design
- Identified market trends, value drivers, and cost efficiencies. Completed 80 transactions, average ROI of 100%

MARKETING AND SALES - LUXURY GOODS AND APPAREL SECTOR—CHARLOTTESVILLE, VA

2002-2008

- Directed product management and brand strategy using competitive analysis and consumer feedback
- · Negotiated contracts with luxury goods companies, managed accounts, profits, losses, and inventories
- Top sales consultant, tailor, and head of product selection requiring constant knowledge of industry trends
- Highly experienced in client management, consumer centric drivers, client acquisition and retention
- Performed business analytics, assessed market trends, facilitated business growth strategy, increasing profits 25%

PERSONAL & TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Extensive experience in leading and managing large scale projects. Entrepreneurial and results-driven achiever.
- Strong understanding of operational process, strategic planning, value/synergy realization, and agile scaling
- · Excellent interpersonal, communication, and sales skills. Capable of handling fast paced environments
- Proven ability to translate client objectives into deliverable designs and solutions that address complex situations
- Experienced with Power Point, Excel. Strong analytical, quantitative, and conceptual thinking
- Ability to travel extensively for work, experienced in leading multi-cultural teams in various business environments

INTERESTS

• Vintage cars, Great Danes, industrial design, exploring Asia, experiencing new cultures, surmounting insurmountable tasks